

PROFILE

I am a dynamic and energetic Project Manager who believes that technology in the realm of business must serve a business and its users, and not the other way around. In my 7+ years of managing technology projects, I have come to believe that all successful technology deployments begin with a focus on the user experience. A positive user experience engages the user to provide feedback for the technology to improve. prolonging the technology's life cycle, and allowing the technology to be accepted into the organization's culture as yet another opportunity for continuous improvement.

I am at my best when given the opportunity to bring a solution to an organization that first solves a problem, engages its users, and making their "what-ifs" into reality.

I look forward to a conversation with you.

CONTACT

PHONE: 416-402-9766

WFRSITE:

https://ninjagirl2018.github.io/Updated Porfolio/

EMAIL: awan9796@gmail.com

ADA WAN

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT PROJECT MANAGER

EDUCATION

Sept 2019 - Current

University of Toronto, School of Continuing Studies – Full Stack Web Development Program

1996 - 2000

University of Toronto, Bachelor of Arts (Hons.) – Political Science

WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelance

April, 2018 – Present

Freelance custom software development Project Manager – 4 Active projects – vertical: Non-profit and Trade Unions – Custom Database builds for Membership Tracking, EDM Databases and workflows

Idealogical Systems Inc. – Special Projects Project Manager August 2015-April 2018

Account manager to key accounts and Project Manager on any infrastructure and custom development projects deployed at each key account – Managed life cycle of entire projects from needs analysis, to quoting and deployment metrics, as well as scope management

Idealogical Systems Inc. – Account Manager (Key Accounts)

October, 2008 – July, 2015

Managed key accounts for company by monitoring client needs through regular contact and meetings and communicating requirements to technical team. Gained insight into the critical relationship between business processes and IT budget planning. Honed the critical skill of moving discussions between business requirements as well as technical requirements.

KEY SKILLS

- 1. 5+ Years: Requirements Gathering, Needs Analysis, Data Analysis
- 5+ Years: Project planning, resource planning, budget planning, client management throughout the project life cycle, management of technical resources, project timelines and resource allocation across technical teams and technical tools
- 3. 8+ Years: Adept at translating business requirements into technical requirements and vice versa, process flows, wireframing
- 4. Comfortable with database technologies and EDM Technologies and best practices, business intelligence and report design;
- 5. My years in account management have given me the insight that UX is the driver for all successful deployments, and all my work, regardless of client or technology, is UX driven